American Montessori Society Records 2006.0230
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series X: Historical Articles and Papers, undated, 1915-
  - Subseries B: Articles on the History of the Montessori Movement and Method, undated
    - Articles on the History of the Montessori Movement and Method, undated (Box 11:, Folder 3-5)
  - Subseries C: Robert G. Buckenmeyer Papers, undated
    - Robert G. Buckenmeyer Transcripts and Manuscripts, undated (Box 11:, Folder 6)
  - Subseries D: Sol Cohen's Articles on the History of Montessori, undated
    - Sol Cohen's Articles on the History of Montessori, undated (Box 11:, Folder 7)
  - Subseries E: Ray and Lucille Franchi Papers, undated
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 11:, Folder 8)
    - Lectures by Maria Montessori, 1915 (Box 11:, Folder 9)
    - "Maria Montessori: A Centenary Anthropology,", undated (Box 11:, Folder 10)
    - "Letters to Susan, A Discouraged Teacher,", undated (Box 12:, Folder 11)
    - "Two Educational Giants Philosophize,", undated (Box 12:, Folder 12)
  - Subseries F: E.M. Standing Papers, undated
    - Notes by E.M. Standing from Maria Montessori's Lectures, undated (Box 12:, Folder 13)
  - Subseries G: Lakshmi A. Kripalani Papers, undated, 1945-2005
    - 3 VHS tapes of L. Kripalani, undated (Box 104)
    - Association Motessori Internationale (AMI), undated, 1967-1987 (Box 96:, Folder 1)
    - AMI Certification, 1974 (Box 104)
    - AMI Conference, Amsterdam, The Netherlands, 1970 July (Box 96:, Folder 2)
    - AMI Congress, Italy, 1970 (Box 101)
    - AMI Conference notes, 1974 August (Box 96:, Folder 3)
    - AMI Congress, Munich, Austria, 1977 July (Box 96:, Folder 4)
    - AMI Conference, Amsterdam, Holland, 1978 (Box 96:, Folder 5)
    - AMI membership, 1973, 1983 (Box 96:, Folder 6)
    - AMI Congress songs, undated (Box 96:, Folder 7)
    - AMI, Questions about, undated (Box 96:, Folder 8)
    - AMI- USA, 1986 (Box 104)
    - AMI- USA Refresher course, St. Louis, MO, 1987 January 16-19 (Box 96:, Folder 9)
    - AMI- USA sixth annual refresher course, Dallas, Texas, 1991 February (Box 104)
    - Application to Rutgers University, undated, 1975, 1978 (Box 104)
    - Articles, undated, 2004 (Box 104)
    - Clippings: L. Kripalani, undated, 1974-2005 (Box 104)
    - Conference, 2002 (Box 104)
    - Conferences and Teacher's Training meetings, undated (Box 104)
    - Correspondence-- AMI, 1982-1984 (Box 104)
    - Correspondence-- AMS, 1962-1966 (Box 96:, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence-- Brazil, 1984 (Box 104)
    - Correspondence--Special, undated, 1965-1982 (Box 96:, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence--Thank yous, 1971-1975 (Box 96:, Folder 12)
    - Daoust, Carolyn Jean dissertation (TS), undated (Box 104)
    - Day Care, undated (Box 96:, Folder 13)
      General note
      TMs, multiple versions
    - Diploma, 1972 (Box 96:, Folder 14)
    - Evaluation, undated (Box 96:, Folder 15)
    - Flyers, 1981 (Box 96:, Folder 16)
    - Graduates contributions, undated, 1971 (Box 104)
    - Hinduasi Publicity, 1970 (Box 96:, Folder 17)
    - International trip, 1982-1983 (Box 96:, Folder 18)
    - Lecture notes, 1970 (Box 104)
    - Lectures by Mario Montessori, 1946 (Box 97:, Folder 1)
    - Manuscripts, undated, 1986, 1991 (Box 104)
    - Maria Montessori Lecture Notes, transcribed from stenographer's notes by Lakshmi A. Kripalani, 1946 (Box 98)
    - Maria Montessori quotes, undated (Box 97:, Folder 2)
    - Maria Montessori Training Course No. 7, [1946] (Box 100)
    - Maria Montessori Training Course No. 7 Material Book, [1946] (Box 99)
    - Mario Montessori talks, 1983-1984 (Box 97:, Folder 3)
    - Memoirs of Acquiring Independence, undated (Box 97:, Folder 4)
    - Montessori articles, undated (Box 97:, Folder 5)
    - Montessori core curriculum, 1998 June 16 (Box 97:, Folder 6)
    - Montessori Teacher Training Center of New Jersey, undated, 1971 (Box 97:, Folder 7)
    - Montessori training in Australia, 1978 (Box 97:, Folder 8)
    - New Jersey State Senate Resolution, 1970 April 9 (Box 101)
    - Notes, undated (Box 104)
    - Notes, undated, 1974 (Box 97:, Folder 9)
    - Notes, 1986 (Box 104)
    - Observation report, 1963 (Box 97:, Folder 10)
    - Personal materials, undated, 1946 (Box 97:, Folder 11)
    - Photographic print ( Hindustan Scouts Association), 1945 (Box 100)
    - Photographic print (computer generated-- L. Kripalani (Box 104)
    - Research, undated (Box 97:, Folder 12)
    - Speeches, 1972 (Box 97:, Folder 13)
    - Teacher Training, 1981 (Box 104)
    - Trainer's Conference, Baarn, 1974 (Box 97:, Folder 14)
    - Trainer's Meeting, 1986 (Box 104)
    - Writings, 1962-1965 (Box 97:, Folder 15)
  - Subseries H: Edith Cary Papers, 1955-1956
    - Notebooks (2), 1955-1956 (Box 102)
  - Subseries I: Mildred W. Harford, undated
    - Personal files, undated (Box 103)
  - Subseries J: Hannah MacLaren, 1963-1965
    - Teacher training, 1963-1965 (Box 103)
  - Subseries K: Marquita Dubach Green, 1960-1979 (Other 2011-0060_1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes: Correspondence and publications.
- Series XI: Research, undated, 1960-circa 1970
  - Subseries A: Articles, undated
    - A - B (Box 12:, Folder 1-2)
    - C - D (Box 12:, Folder 3-4)
    - E - F (Box 13:, Folder 5)
    - G - H (Box 13:, Folder 6)
    - I - J (Box 13:, Folder 7)
    - K - L (Box 13:, Folder 8)
    - M - N (Box 13:, Folder 9)
    - O - P (Box 13:, Folder 10)
    - Q - R (Box 13:, Folder 11)
    - S - T (Box 13:, Folder 12)
    - U - V (Box 13:, Folder 13)
    - W - X (Box 13:, Folder 14)
    - Y - Z (Box 13:, Folder 15)
  - Subseries B: Bibliographies and Abstracts, undated
    - Subject Index Cards (Box 14)
    - Bibliographies (Box 15:, Folder 16)
    - Abstracts (Box 15:, Folder 17)
- Series XII: Consultation Program, undated, 1965-1979
  - Subseries A: Reports, Lists and Handbooks, undated, 1965-1971
    - Consultation reports, undated (Box 15:, Folder 1)
    - Consultation Expense Reports, undated (Box 15:, Folder 2)
    - Consultation Report Forms, undated (Box 15:, Folder 3)
    - Lists of AMS School Visitors, undated (Box 15:, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reports to the AMS Board of Directors, 1965-1971 (Box 15:, Folder 5)
    - Consultation Services Handbooks, undated (Box 15:, Folder 6)
  - Subseries B: General Correspondence, undated
    - Consultation (Box 15:, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: Lilian DeVault Files, undated
    - Lillian DeVault Files (Box 16:, Folder 8)
  - Subseries D: Sonja M. Donahue Files, undated
    - Sonja M. Donahue Files (Box 16:, Folder 9)
  - Subseries E: Ann Burke Neubert Files, undated
    - Ann Burke Neubert Files (Box 16:, Folder 10)
  - Subseries F: Correspondence to and from Individual Consultants, undated
    - A - B (Box 16:, Folder 11)
    - C - D (Box 16:, Folder 12)
    - E - F (Box 16:, Folder 13)
    - G - H (Box 16:, Folder 14)
    - I - J (Box 16:, Folder 15)
    - K - L (Box 16:, Folder 16)
    - M - N (Box 17:, Folder 17)
    - O - P (Box 17:, Folder 18)
    - Q - R (Box 17:, Folder 19)
    - S - T (Box 17:, Folder 20)
    - U - V (Box 17:, Folder 21)
    - W - X (Box 17:, Folder 22)
    - Y - Z (Box 17:, Folder 23)
- Series XIII: Seminars and Conferences, undated, 1963-1990
  - List of AMS Seminars, 1963-1989 (Box 17:, Folder 1)
  - Conference Brochures, 1985-1990 (Box 17:, Folder 2)
  - AMS Seminar Registration Lists, 1963-1977 (Box 18:, Folder 3)
  - 19th International Montessori Congress, Amsterdam, 1979 April (Box 18:, Folder 4)
  - AMS International Symposium, Athens, 1979 (Box 18:, Folder 5-6)
  - AMS International Symposium, Papers Read at the Symposium, 1979 (Box 18:, Folder 7)
  - Regional Seminar, Silver Spring, MS, 1979 (Box 18:, Folder 8)
  - AMS/ CND West Coast Regional Seminar, Belmont, CA, 1979 April (Box 18:, Folder 9)
  - Annual Seminar, Memphis, TN, 1982 June (Box 18:, Folder 10)
  - Southeastern Regional Conference, Miami, FL, 1984 February (Box 19:, Folder 11)
  - Western Regional Conference, San Diego, CA, 1984 April (Box 19:, Folder 12)
  - National Seminar, Evaston, IL, 1984 June (Box 19:, Folder 13-14)
  - National Seminar, Evaston, IL, Exhibits and Finances, 1984 June (Box 19:, Folder 15)
  - AMS Southwest Regional Conference, Houston, Texas, 1984 November (Box 20:, Folder 16)
  - AMS Western Regional Conference, Honolulu, HI, 1985 February (Box 21:, Folder 17)
  - Conference, Dayton, OH, 1985 November (Box 21:, Folder 18)
  - AMS 25th Anniversary Seminar, Washington, D.C., Ad Hoc Committee, 1985 April (Box 21:, Folder 19)
  - AMS 25th Anniversary Seminar, Washington, D.C., Exhibitors, 1985 April (Box 21:, Folder 20)
  - AMS 25th Anniversary Seminar, Washington,D.C., Registration, Presenters, 1985 April (Box 21:, Folder 21)
  - AMS 25th Anniversary Seminar, Washington, D.C., Evaluation Forms, 1985 April (Box 21:, Folder 22)
  - AMS 25th Anniversary Seminar, Washington,D.C., Finances, 1985 April (Box 21:, Folder 23)
  - Regional Conference, Tampa, FL, 1986 February (Box 21:, Folder 24)
  - Peace and Education Regional Conference, New York, NY, 1986 April (Box 21:, Folder 25)
  - AMS Annual Seminar, San Francisco, CA, Exhibitors, 1986 April (Box 21:, Folder 26)
  - AMS Annual Seminar, San Francisco, CA, Registration, 1986 April (Box 21:, Folder 27)
  - Early Education/Montessori Regional Conference, St. Paul, MN, 1986 June (Box 21:, Folder 28)
  - AMS Eastern Regional Conference, Wilmington, DE, 1986 November (Box 21:, Folder 29)
  - Fall Regional Conference, Boston, MA, 1987 October - November (Box 21:, Folder 30)
  - AMS Western Regional Conference, Berkeley, CA, 1988 February (Box 21:, Folder 31)
  - National Seminar, Cincinnati, OH, 1988 April (Box 21:, Folder 32)
  - National Conference, Dallas, TX, 1989 April (Box 21:, Folder 33)
- Series XIV: AMS Publications, undated, 1960-1999
  [Note: The publications themselves have been removed from the collection, cataloged and are located in Dodd Periodicals.]
  - Subseries A: American Montessori Society Bulletin, 1960-1981
    - List of Published AMS Bulletins, 1960-1981 (Box 22)
    - American Montessori Society Bulletin (incomplete), 1961-1981
  - Subseries B: AMS Educational Bulletin, 1963-1964
    - AMS Educational Bulletin, 1963-1964
  - Subseries C: AMS News, 1970-1979
    - AMS News (incomplete), 1970-1979
  - Subseries D: AMS Newsletter, 1970
    - AMS Newsletter, 1970
  - Subseries E: American Montessori Society Newsletter (New Series), 1980-1981
    - American Montessori Society Newsletter, 1980-1981
  - Subseries F: AMS News Notes, 1963-1969
    - AMS News Notes (incomplete), 1963-1969
  - Subseries G: AMS School Heads Network, 1989-1995
    - AMS School Heads Network (incomplete), 1989-1995
  - Subseries H: AMS Teacher News, 1973-1974
    - AMS Teacher News, 1973-1974
  - Subseries I: Constructive Triangle, undated, 1968-1989
    - Articles and indexes, typescript, undated (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1974 (Box 23)
    - Constructive Triangle, 1968-1989
  - Subseries J: Public School Montessorian, 1988-1998
    - Public School Montessorian, 1988-1998
  - Subseries K: Montessori Life, 1989-1999
    - Montessori Life, 1989-1999
- Series XV: Brochures, Pamphlets, Publicity and Press Releases, undated
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Publicity and Press Releases, undated (Box 24:, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook: Untitled, undated (Box 24:, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook: Disabilities and Handicaps, undated (Box 24:, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook: Observing and Recording Children, undated (Box 24:, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook: What is the Montessori Method?, undated (Box 24:, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook: For Parents and Teachers, undated (Box 24:, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook: Music--Movement--Games, undated (Box 25:, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook: Infants and Toddlers, undated (Box 25:, Folder 8)
- Series XVI: Correspondence and Publicity for AMS Films, undated, 1973
  - Montessori Films: Correspondence, Publicity, Photographs, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1)
  - AMS Slide/Film Contest, 1973 (Box 25:, Folder 2)
- Series XVII: Montessori and AMS-affiliated Schools, undated, 1962-1976
  - Montessori Schools, undated (Box 25:, Folder 1)
  - Bylaws of Montessori Schools and Associations, undated (Box 25:, Folder 2)
  - Lists of AMS-Affiliated Schools, 1962-1967 (Box 25:, Folder 3)
  - Lists of AMS-Affiliated Schools, 1967-1976 (Box 25:, Folder 4)
  - Overview of AMS-Affiliated Schools, undated (Box 26:, Folder 5)
  - Study Groups That Did Not Affiliate, undated (Box 26:, Folder 6)
  - Barrie Day School-- Silver Spring, MD, undated (Box 26:, Folder 7)
  - Cazenovia Children's Center-- Cazenovia, NY, undated (Box 26:, Folder 8)
  - Compton Unified School District: Bilingual/Bicultural Preschool Education Program, 1972-1973 (Box 26:, Folder 9)
  - Gloria Dei School-- Dayton, OH, undated (Box 26:, Folder 10)
  - Red Cloud Indian School-- Pine Ridge, SD, undated (Box 26:, Folder 11)
  - Seton Little People's Montessori School Handbook, 1971 (Box 26:, Folder 12)
  - How to Start a Montessori School, undated (Box 26:, Folder 13)
  - AMS School Guidelines, undated (Box 26:, Folder 14)
  - AMS Affiliate Questionnaires and Application Information, undated (Box 26:, Folder 15)
  - Directories, undated (Box 26:, Folder 16)
  - Statistical Data on School Affiliates, undated (Box 26:, Folder 17)
  - Statistical Tabulations From School Questionnaires, 1971-1972 (Box 27:, Folder 18)
  - Regional Group Affiliation, undated (Box 27:, Folder 19)
  - Affiliate Membership Appeals, undated (Box 27:, Folder 20)
  - Admissions Forms, Agreements, and Policies, undated (Box 27:, Folder 21)
  - Tuition Agreements, undated (Box 27:, Folder 22)
- Series XVIII: Child Development Associate Consortium, undated, circa 1972-1976
  - Child Development Associate Consortium, undated (Box 27:, Folder 1-2)
- Series XIX: Comite Hispano Montessori, undated, circa 1975-1991
  - General Information, undated (Box 28:, Folder 1)
  - Consultation Reports, undated (Box 28:, Folder 2)
  - Seminar, Monterrey, Mexico, 1979 June (Box 28:, Folder 3)
- Series XX: Educational Groups and Organizations, undated
  - Creative Playthings, Inc., undated (Box 28:, Folder 1)
  - ERIC, undated (Box 28:, Folder 2)
  - Family learning Center, Rochester City School District, Rochester, NY, undated (Box 28:, Folder 3)
  - Home Schooling Organizations, undated (Box 28:, Folder 4)
  - Home Study Course in Modern Montessori Teaching (School of Modern Montessori), undated (Box 28:, Folder 5)
  - National Association for Family Day Care, undated (Box 28:, Folder 6)
  - Waldorf Institute/ Rudolf Steiner School, undated (Box 28:, Folder 7)
  - Waldorf--Montessori Comparison, undated (Box 28:, Folder 8)
- Series XXI: Non-AMS Publications, undated
  - Non- AMS Publications, undated (Box 28:, Folder 1)
  - AMI Communications, undated (Box 28:, Folder 2)
- Series XXII: Sound Recordings, undated, 1969-2005
  - Subseries A: Audiocassettes, undated, 1972-2005
    - "The American Montessori Society for Elementary Classes (Part 1/2)"/Rambusch, Kalpin, and Townsend [#16A/B], undated (Box 33:, Folder ACass_55-56)
    - "Are We Communicating or Just Talking?" Susan Thoroux and Nancy Rambusch, undated (Box 33:, Folder ACass_50)
    - Begley, Mary-Whitby, 1997 May 8 (Box 73:, Folder ACass_86)
    - "Childhood and Society in the Age of Technology"/ Bob Korngold, undated (Box 32:, Folder ACass_44)
    - "Cooking"/San Filipp, Waters - "Science"/ Helen Mills, undated (Box 33:, Folder ACass_53)
    - "The Democratic Family"/ Oscar C. Christensen, undated (Box 33:, Folder ACass_48)
    - "Difference Is the Same"/Mansfield, undated (Box 32:, Folder ACass_33-34)
    - "Family Counseling"/ Oscar C. Christensen, undated (Box 33:, Folder ACass_49)
    - General Meeting, undated (Box 29:, Folder ACass_60)
    - General Meeting: Susan Thoroux and Nancy Rambusch, undated (Box 29:, Folder ACass_60)
    - "Guidelines for Parenting"/Lewis, undated (Box 32:, Folder ACass_35-36)
    - "Infants and Toddlers in Nature"/Varga, undated (Box 32:, Folder ACass_37-38)
    - "Ka'aina a me ke kai-Land and Sea"/Ballantine, undated (Box 32:, Folder ACass_39)
    - "Language Development" and Board Meeting ( Norristown, Pennsylvania), undated (Box 31:, Folder ACass_30)
    - " Maria Montessori-Early Feminist"/ Rita Kramer, undated (Box 31:, Folder ACass_31)
    - "Montessori Education: An Overview", undated (Box 33:, Folder ACass_51)
    - Montessori's Cosmic View/Trudeau, undated (Box 32:, Folder ACass_40)
    - Music, Jean Miller, undated (Box 33:, Folder ACass_59)
    - Nancy McCormick Rambusch: Audio Cassettes of Presentations to the American Montessori Society, undated (Box 79:, Folder ACass_110)
      24 Tapes
    - New England Regional Conference: Childhood and Society in the Age of Technology, undated (Box 79:, Folder ACass_109)
      Tapes #1-29, missing #1, 4, 13-16, 21, 23, 28
    - "Nature and the Young Child"/Bogart, undated (Box 32:, Folder ACass_41)
    - "One World-One People"/Renton, undated (Box 32:, Folder ACass_42-43)
    - Opening General Session, undated (Box 33:, Folder ACass_45-46)
    - "Playground Planning and Design"/ Nelson Van Judah, undated (Box 33:, Folder ACass_54)
    - "The Relevancy and Future of Montessori Education" Music/ Jean Miller, undated (Box 33:, Folder ACass_52)
    - Conference, Albert Joosten, undated (Box 105:, Folder ac_166)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd19
    - Dialog Childcare, undated (Box 105:, Folder ac_169)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd22
    - Infant Care, February 21 (Box 105:, Folder ac_167)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd20
    - "The Unfolding of the Special Child"/Dudock, undated (Box 33:, Folder ACass_47)
    - L. Kripalani Children USA, undated (Box 105:, Folder ac_163)
    - Observation (mediation) seminar, undated (Box 105:, Folder ac_174)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd27
    - Graduation, R. Saltzman, 1970 (Box 105:, Folder ac_168)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd21
    - Music workshop 1st Session Morning, Graduation, 1971 (Box 105:, Folder ac_162)
    - Cosmic Education, Salzmann, Montessori, Light, San Francisco UNESCO, 1972 March 25 (Box 105:, Folder ac_170)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd23
    - Seminar: Nancy Rambusch, San Francisco, CA, 1972 June 12 (Box 29:, Folder ACass_1)
    - Seminar: General Session and "Goal of Moral Education"/ Susan Thoroux, Boston, MA, 1974 June (Box 29:, Folder ACass_2)
    - "Montessori Education in America"/ Ann F. Lucas, 1976 (Box 29:, Folder ACass_3)
    - "Piaget and Montessori: Similarities and Differences"/ David S. Kuschner, 1976 (Box 29:, Folder ACass_4)
    - Seminar: "Practical Applications of Piaget"/ David Elkind, Philadelphia, PA, 1977 June (Box 29:, Folder ACass_5)
    - Gravel, Douglas, 1999 Febraury 15 (Box 73:, Folder ACass_79)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd37
    - 20th Anniversary Seminar, 1980 June
      - MOO1: "History of AMS" (Box 29:, Folder ACass_6)
      - MOO2: Keynote/Hechinger (Box 29:, Folder ACass_7)
      - MOO3: "Lasting Effects" (Box 29:, Folder ACass_8)
      - MOO4: "Montessori in Public"/Mathisen (Box 29:, Folder ACass_9)
      - MOO5: "Child's Viewpoint"/ Dorothy Dooly (Box 29:, Folder ACass_10)
      - MOO6: "First Language"/ Barbara Last (Box 29:, Folder ACass_11)
      - MOO7: Workshop/ Ann Rogovin (Box 29:, Folder ACass_12)
      - MOO8: "Ideas and Ideals"/ Harold Taylor (Box 30:, Folder ACass_13)
      - MOO9: Ruth Gans and Selina Perry (Box 30:, Folder ACass_14)
      - MO10: Infant Panel/Gravel et al. (Box 30:, Folder ACass_15)
      - MO11: "Environments"/Honig et al. [2 tapes] (Box 30:, Folder ACass_16)
      - MO11: "Environments"/Honig et al. [2 tapes] (Box 30:, Folder ACass_17)
      - MO13: "Cognitive Movement"/Carbon-Cone (Box 30:, Folder ACass_18)
      - MO14: "Missing Link"/ James Gibbons (Box 30:, Folder ACass_19)
      - MO15: "Special Ed Response"/Koetler (Box 30:, Folder ACass_20)
      - MO17: "With a Small M"/ Nancy Rambusch (Box 30:, Folder ACass_21)
      - MO19: "Toddler"/Vargas (Box 30:, Folder ACass_22)
      - MO20: Kolinowski (Box 30:, Folder ACass_23)
      - MO22: "Forerunners"/Lane (Box 30:, Folder ACass_24)
      - MO23: "Perceptive Development" (Box 31:, Folder ACass_25)
      - MO24: "Infants-Book"/Heins (Box 31:, Folder ACass_26)
    - 21st Annual Seminar: Fantasy and creativity in the Life of the Child, 1981 (Box 78:, Folder ACass_105)
      Tapes W5A, W5C, GS1-3, MS1-2, W1A-D, W2A-C, W6B-D
    - Karachi Workshop I and II, 1982 December 12 (Box 105:, Folder ac_164)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd17a-d
    - Graduation, Mayor Mary Mochary, 1982 (Box 105:, Folder ac_165)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd18
    - 22nd Annual Seminar: Montessori a definition, 1982 (Box 79:, Folder ACass_111)
      Tapes #1-36, BQ, missing #1, 3, 20, 32, 35
    - Eastern Regional Conference: Craddle of Independence, 1982 (Box 79:, Folder ACass_108)
      Tapes GS1, W1A, W1C-D, W2A, W2C-D, W3A-B, W4C-D, W5A, W5D, W6B-D
    - Eastern Regional Conference: Mind, Body, Movement: The Elements of Education, Philadelphia, PA, 1982 (Box 83/91:, Folder ACass_127)
      Tapes OA1, W1A-D, W2A, W2C-D, W3B, W3D, KN1, W4C-D, W5B-C, W6A, W6C-D, W7A-C, W8A-D, W9A, W9C
    - Northwest Regional Conference: Chance Favors the Prepared Mind, 1982 (Box 88:, Folder ACass_149)
      Tapes #1-16
    - Graduation Pakistan Mont. Ass. 15th Miss K Ex. Examine Salman Frook Chief guest and Quranby Children, 1982 December 14 (Box 105:, Folder ac_161)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd16
    - Western Regional Seminar: Montessori in the 80's, Visions and Reality, 1983 (Box 86:, Folder ACass_140)
      Tapes #1-35, missing #2, 7,10, 18, 23, 27
    - 23rd Annual Seminar: Children Guiding Tomorrow's Minds Today, The Future is Now, 1983 June 16 - 19 (Box 83/91:, Folder ACass_126)
      Tapes GS1-2, MS1-5, TH1-2, 1WS, 3WS, 5WS, 8WS-10WS, 12WS-15WS, 17WS, #3-5, 8, 10-98, missing #18, 21, 23, 28-30, 32-38, 41, 44, 48-49, 52-54, 57, 60-62, 66, 69-72, 75, 78-79, 81-83, 87-89, 92-93, 95-97
    - 24th Annual Seminar: Celebrate the Child within, 1984 (Box 79:, Folder ACass_106)
      T #1-43, missing #20, 25-27, 30-31, 34, 36, 40
    - Western Regional Seminar: Living, Loving, Learning, San Diego, CA, 1984 April 27 - 29 (Box 85:, Folder ACass_136)
      Tapes #1-21, missing #8-9, 20
    - Dr. Anna Maria, Dr. Judy Sylvania, 1984 July 29 (Box 105:, Folder ac_173)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd26
    - Education for a new World, Houston, TX, 1984 November (Box 79:, Folder ACass_107)
      Tapes #1-19, missing #1, 11, 14
    - Education for a New World, Houston, TX, 1984 November (Box 87:, Folder ACass_145)
      Tapes #23-27
    - 25 years Anniversary Seminar, 1985 (Box 88:, Folder ACass_148)
      Tapes #1-46, missing #7, 15, 29-30, 35, 45
    - National Seminar: Montessori 75 years in America, 1986 (Box 88:, Folder ACass_151)
      Tapes #1-44, missing #1A, 2, 12, 25, 36
    - AMS Education Looks at Itself, Eastern Regional Seminar, Wilminington, DE, 1986 (Box 86:, Folder ACass_139)
      Tapes #1-33, missing #8-11, 13-15, 18, 22, 24, 26-29
    - Regional Seminar: Montessori--A New Visibility, Tampa, FL, 1986 (Box 86:, Folder ACass_141)
      Tapes #1-18
    - Seasonal Workshop, Cleveland, Ohio, 1986 February 11 (Box 105:, Folder ac_171)
      Use copy 2006-0230.cd24
    - Regional Conference, Wilmington, Delaware: "Montessori-Past and Future"/ Nancy McCormick Rambusch [2 tapes], 1986 November (Box 31:, Folder ACass_27-28)
    - 27th Annual Seminar: Environmental Imprints on Children of the Space Age, Miami Beach, FL, 1987 (Box 89:, Folder ACass_152)
      Tapes #1-26
    - Regional Seminar: Children and Families in the Age of Technology, Boston, MA, 1987 October 31 - November 1 (Box 85:, Folder ACass_138)
      Tapes #1-39, missing #6, 9, 22-23, 32
    - The Inner World of the Child, Berkeley, CA, 1988 February (Box 84:, Folder ACass_131)
      Tapes #1-61, missing #2-4, 9-10, 12, 19-22, 24, 31, 38-39, 41, 44, 51